A Guide to the Papers of John Powell, 1888-1978, n.d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I.: Correspondence
  - Subseries A.: Correspondence of John and Louise Powell
    - Section 1.: Chronological Correspondence
      - Correspondence, September 1938, 54 items. (Box-folder 14:7)
        Correspondents include John A. Blakemore; Rebecca [Brockenbrough]; John S. Chapman; Richard Chase; George Crandall; F. Meredith Dietz, editor, Southern Literary Messenger; Vera Bull Hull; George [Pullen Jackson]; Thomas Catesby Jones; Myron M. Kahn; William Casimar Mayfarth; William Shands Meacham; Helen Mobert; Wilfrid Pyle to William Mayforth; Margaret Seward; Edward R. Stettinius, Jr.; C. G. Terwilliger; Lelia J. Triplett; Jerry Vogel.
        Letters from John Powell to: Vera Bull Hull; Helen Mobert; Miss Robert; Mr. Ruskin; George Tucker.
        Letters from Louise Powell to: John [Blakemore]; Mr. Beck; Mr. Dietz; Miss Hayter; Mr. Ruskin; Mr. Slemp; [Grace] Vanamee.
      - Correspondence, October 1938 (Box-folder 14:8)
        Correspondents include Leon Barzin; Dorothy Bevard; Mrs. E. H. Cahill; Harry Clemons; James Constantine; George Crandall; Albert VonDoenhoff; Ruth Ferry; L. J. Fitzgerald; Mrs. Alice Hancock; Roma Devonne Hempstead; Josef Hofman; Frederick R. Huber; Maud Karpeles; Harold Morris; Julia Fuqua Ober Wilfrid Pyle; Virginia Richardson; Margaret Seward; Avery Slack; Lois Talbert; Kate Weichert; Fletcher Woodward.
        Letter from John Powell to Edward R. Stettinius, Jr.
      - Correspondence, November 1938, 57 items. (Box-folder 14:9)
        Correspondents include Alfred T. Adams; Raimonde and Martha Aubrey; J. Paul Berl; Mary and Barry Bingham; Betty Brockenbrough; Tom Bryan; [Edith, Adele, and Adeline]; Nannie Campbell; Richard Chase; F. Meredith Dietz, editor, Southern Literary Messenger; Gertrude Fitzhugh; Marion and Stanley Fletcher; Mildred Fletcher; Dr. J. Shelton Horsley; Vera Bull Hull to Thomas Catesby Jones; Ernest Hutcheson; Elsie Illingworth; Mr. and Mrs. J. Winston Johns; Roma Devonne Hempstead; Milton Kaye; Mrs. G. F. Kemper; Wlademir Lakond; Jack Langstaff; Llangollen; J. Adolph Leftwich; Mrs. Frances McFarland; Marjorie Megargel; I. Van. Meter, Time Magazine; Laird Miller; Margaret Munn; James Murphy to Vera Bull Hull; John Lloyd Newcomb; Grace Newcomb; Anne Powers; Harry Rogers Pratt; Herbert Ricker; Austin Ross; Hilton Rufty; Felix Salmond; Robert E. Simon; Ruth and Myron Taylor; Grace Vanamee; W. D. Weatherford.
        Letters from John Powell to: Hartwell Cabell; Marks Levine.
        Letters from Louise Powell to Julia Fuqua Ober.
      - Correspondence, December 1938, 39 items. (Box-folder 14:10)
        Correspondents include Annabel Morris Buchanan; Ann Cabell; Jim Chisholm; Chalmers Clifton; Richard and Kay Chase; Louise Edmunds; M. B. Gates; Armistead Heindl; Ernest Hutcheson; Hans Kindler; Marks Levine; Maud C. Lile; Murray M. McGuire; Cary McMurran; Alice Palmer; Mary M. Powell; Wanda Clifton; Harry Rogers Pratt; Mary V. Robertson; Hilton Rufty; Myrtle Russell; Ruth and Nikolai Sokoloff; Jane Stoner; Patsey Taylor; Maria Kennedy Tod; Grace Vanamee; Mabel McBain Whilter; Hubertus Zu Loewenstein.
      - Correspondence, 1938, 58 items. (Box-folder 14:11)
        Louise Powell. Correspondents include Edith Kent Carpenter; Virginia S. Carper; Chalmers Clifton; Minnie Cocke; Grace B. Copeland; Earnest Cox; Mollie Darling; Alice Dukes; Knotty Elswuth; Jeannette F. Green; Orne Lathan Hatches; Walter Houston; B. J. Hubbard; Dr. William E. Hudson; Imgart Hutcheson; Thomas Catesby Jones; Ernest LaPrade; Daniel Gregory Mason; Mary Mason; Harold Morris; Seton C. Morris; Julia Fuqua Ober; Wilfrid Pyle; Wilfrid Pyle to William C. Mayfarth; Bobby Roberts; J. Z. Ruskin; Edna Shaeffer; Nathalie P. Small; Elizabeth Teuch to Vera Bull Hull; Mercye Tucker; Grace Vanamee.
      - Correspondence, January 1939, 57 items. (Box-folder 15:1)
        Correspondents include May Ball; Horton Barker; Mrs. Murray Boocock; Carl W. Broman; Esther F. Brookes; C. C. Cappel; Henri Lloyd Clement; E. H. Droop; Mary B. Dunlap; Stella J. Dunn; Mary O. Eddy; Stanley Fletcher; May Gadd; T. Armistead Heindl; Hannah Hodgdon; Edwin Hughes;Vera Bull Hull; Irmgart Hutcheson; Hans Kindler; Wlademir Lakond; Ernest LaPrade; B. F. D. Runk; Hessie Cruise Scott; Edward R. Stettinius, Jr.; Albert Stoessel; Jean Thomas; Maria Kennedy Tod; Henry Cowles Whitehead.
      - Correspondence, February 1939, 40 items. (Box-folder 15:2)
        Correspondents include Louise C. Ball; Curtis Bishop; Harriet Betty Boas; Annabel Morris Buchanan; Mary O. Eddy; Sarah Hirsohn; Hannah Hodgdon; LeRoy Hodges; Vera Bull Hull; Sarah Gertrude Knott; Ernest LaPrade; Clay Morgan; C. A. Overton, Jr.; F. H. Poston; H. R. Pratt; Hilton Rufty; Hugh White.
      - Correspondence, March- May 1939, 65 items. (Box-folder 15:3)
        Correspondents include Betty Borger; Annabel Morris Buchanan; C. C. Cappel; Frank P. Crasto, Jr.; Anne Hyde Choate; D. N. Davidson; Francis Duke; Rowland W. Dunham; Ruth M. Ferry; Samuel Fieldman; Frances R. Forman; M. B. Gates; Charles E. Griffith; Madeline A. Harman; Hannah Hodgdon; Vera Bull Hull; Pierre V. R. Key; Wlademir Lakond; Ernest LaPrade; Marks Levine; Juanita Frey Ludwigs; A. N. Marquis; Ruth Ottaway; John G. Paine; Mary Powell; Wanda Clifton; Mary Minor Richardson; Mary Schultz; Sigmund Spaeth; Robert L. Stearns; Lamar Stringfield; C. G. Terwilliger; G. A. Thilow; Sarah Watson; Henrietta Booth Wise.
      - Correspondence, June-August 1939, 59 items. (Box-folder 15:4)
        Correspondents include Walter Alderman; Curtis Bishop; Walter R. Bishop; John A. Blakemore; Nathan Broder; John C. Campbell; Olive D. Campbell; D. N. Davidson; F. Meredith Dietz; May Garrettson Evans; Eugene H. Fischer; Harry Friedgut; L. Bane Hayter; Dr. William E. Hudson; Vera Bull Hull; Marks Levine; Juanita Frey Ludwigs; Jacquelyn McWin; Helen Mobert; Margaret Munn; Ruth Ottaway; Harry Rogers Pratt; Luther A. Richman; W. S. Rodman; Hilton Rufty; Ethel Anson Steckham; Lamar Stringfield; Richard W. Talley; W. R. Wilkerson.
      - Correspondence, September-October 1939, 55 items. (Box-folder 15:5)
        Correspondents include Ella G. Agnew; May Ball; John Barbirolli; Curtis Bishop; Ada Bolanz; Nathan Broder; Henry S. Canby; Lloyd W. Chisholm; Mary Bains Davis; Abe Chaddock Edmunds; Leonard Elsmith; Evelyne Ficarria; Helen Forbes; T. Armistead Heidl; M. Ruth Burruss Huff; Cordee Hull; Vera Bull Hull; Mrs. William Witcher Keen; Marks Levine; Henry A. McComas; Margaret Munn; Elise Pager; Ashley Pettis; Mary Minor Richardson; Hilton Rufty; John W. Starnes; Charles A. Thomson; Francis Lee Thurman; C. B. Wohlford.
      - Correspondence, November-December 1939, 41 items. (Box-folder 15:6)
        Correspondents include May Ball; John Barbirolli; John A. Blakemore; Nathan Broder; Olive D. Campbell; Henry S. Canby; Olin Downes; George Engles; George Fischer; Henry H. Fuchs; Charles E. Griffith; Ruth Burruss Huff; Vera Bull Hull; Eunice Kettering; Mattie B. Kumler; Osbourne McConathy; Margaret Munn; John Lloyd Newcomb; Buford Nolting; Patricia Parmelee; Robert Porterfield; F. H. Price; Luther A. Richman; Sylvia Rosenberg; Jane Stoner; Lamar Stringfield; Albert von Doenhoff; Marianne E. Weads; George B. Zehmer.
      - Correspondence, 1939, 46 items. (Box-folder 15:7)
        Correspondents include Selma Burger; Kay Chase; Grace B. Copeland; Mary Gordon Darling; F. Meredith Dietz; Caroline F. Diggs; Mary O. Eddy; W. B. Gates; L. Bane Hayter; Bernard E. Hirons; Charlotte Kent; Ernest LaPrade; Nancey G. Leigh; Florence Landis McKee; Mary Mason; Joyce Napier; Elise Paget; Mrs. Cuthbert Powell; Carol Preston; Helen Seth Smith; Catherine White; Mattie Wohlford.
      - Correspondence, January-February 1940, 54 items. (Box-folder 15:8)
        Correspondents include John Barbirolli; Annabel Morris Buchanan; Bessie D. Burruss; Henry S. Canby; Seth Carroll; Richard Chase; Harry E. Cooper; George Engles; Clarence Flye; Frances R. Forman; J. P. Grovo; Frank E. Hartman; Vera Bull Hull; Dorle Jarmel; T. Catesby Jones; Hans Kindler; Marks Levine; Alpha Corinne Mayfield; Claire McCarthy; Mary S. McCue; Elise Moody; Margaret Munn; Eli E. Oberstein; Patricia Parmelee; Thomas J. Peck; Harry Rogers Pratt; Virginia Richardson; Marion Rous; Frank H. Smith; Andrew R. Summers.
      - Correspondence, March 1940, 34 items. (Box-folder 15:9)
        Correspondents include Willie Gray Allen; Lionel A. Aucoin; May Ball; Curtis Bishop; Milton P. Baline; Carl W. Broman; Harry E. Cooper; John Dickson; James N. Dunlop; Frank E. Hartman; John Tasker Howard; Mary Howe; Mrs. George S. Hurt; Frank McCarthy; Margaret Munn; Eli E. Oberstein; Mildred N. Page; John G. Paine; Benjamin Starr; John Charles Thomas; Florence Tressel; F. Austin Walter; R. P. Wetherld; Mary Louise Wright.
      - Correspondence, April 1940, 35 items. (Box-folder 16:1)
        Correspondents include Carroll E. Beach; Charles Wakefield Cadman; Olive D. Campbell; Henri Lloyd Clement; Nan Crow; Richard H. Dana; John Dickson; Francis Duke; James N. Dunlop; Elliot Griffis; Christine Gunlaugson; Ellen M. Hannah; Mary Howe; Vera Bull Hull; Eunice Lea Kettering; Hans Kindler; Marks Levine; Goddard Lieberson; Claire McCarthy; Duncan McKenzie; Thomas D. McSpadden; William Shands Meacham; John Lloyd Newcomb; John Alex Rorer; Ida Schroeder; Andrew R. Summers.
      - Correspondence, May-June 1940, 36 items. (Box-folder 16:2)
        Correspondents include John A. Blakemore; Nathan Broder; Carl W. Broman; Esther Coburn; Leonard Elsmith; Ellen Hannah; Margaret Hobart; Jess J. Johnston; John Treville Latouche; Henry C. Leigh; Goddard Lieberson; José InÁcio Cabral Lima; Claire McCarthy; E. C. Mills; Margaret Munn; Eli E. Oberstein; Gustave Reese; Mary Minor Richardson; Hilton Rufty; Rosalie Smith; Theodore E. Steinway; Frank Laird Waller; R. P. Wetherald.
      - Correspondence, July-August 1940, 32 items. (Box-folder 16:3)
        Correspondents include H. Hugh Altvaer; Albert G. A. Balz; John A. Blakemore; Ellen Page Brydon; Carter S. Cole; F. Meredith Dietz; James Stone Easley; R. Claude Graham; Percy Grainger; Leo Hart; Lee F. Hartman; Florence D. Heguembourg; Elsie Illingworth; Hans Kindler; Sarah Leigh; May Lindsay-Oliver; Lolita Duncan Manford; Alpha Corinne Mayfield; Claire McCarthy; Jean Meredith; Eli E. Oberstein; Robert Porterfield; Wanda Clifton; Hilton Rufty; M. Stanley-Brown; H. L. Webster.
      - Correspondence, September-October 1940, 33 items. (Box-folder 16:4)
        Correspondents include H. Hugh Altvater; W. R. Bishop; Carl W. Broman; Mary Craighill; Elizabeth R. Davis; Hermene Warlick Eichhorn; A. W. Greiner; Mildred Inevrett; Eunice Lea Kettering; Irene Magness; J. M. Meredith; E. C. Mills; Ethel Newcomb; Eli E. Oberstein; Elise Paget; John G. Paine; Sallie Stephens Perkins; Grace Powell; Rebecca Powell; Herman Reichenlaub; Mary Minor Richardson; Hilton Rufty; Sigmund Spaeth; Grace Wendt; Pauline Wohlford.
      - Correspondence, November-December 1940, 11 items. (Box-folder 16:5)
        Correspondents include Carl W. Broman; Mrs. James Stone Easley; A. W. Greiner; Christine Gunlaugson; Alpha Corinne Mayfield; Edward Nies-Perger; Nick Oglesby; Mary Minor Richardson.
      - Correspondence, January-March 1941, 39 items. (Box-folder 16:6)
        Correspondents include Arthur Baldwin; May Ball; Irving Cheyette; Chalmers Clifton; Mary Cummings Endy; George Engles; Kenneth G. Fiske; May Gadd; Sallie F. Hill; J. M. Sailor Dad Hunt; Mildred Inevrett; Eunice Lea Kettering; Hans Kindler; Mrs. Thomas Lee Melgaard; Margaret Munn; Edouard Nies-Berger; Ruth Ottaway; Mary C. Rowes; Theodore E. Steinway; Russell M. Story; Elsie C. Strickler; Ella Wynn Sulfridge; Maxine Swalin; Mrs. Albert S. J. Tucker; Lyda Terrill Walling.
      - Correspondence, April-July 1941, 65 items. (Box-folder 16:7)
        Correspondents include Hollis P. Allen; Horton Barker; Beulah V. Bennett; Martin Birnbaum; Mrs. R. C. Bowie; Richard Chase; Henri Lloyd Clement; James S. Constantine; Jennie P. Cooke; Judy Bruce deRycke; Hermene Warlick Eichhorn; Ruth M. Ferry; Kenneth Fiske; Lloyd Fitzgerald; Harry Frazier, Jr.; Charles E. Griffith; J. M. Sailor Dad Hunt; Jess J. Johnston; Edwin Kames; Willis Kerr; Pierre V. R. Key; Ernest LaPrade; Dorothy Lawton; Paul Lemay; Alpha Corinne Mayfield; Helen Mobert; Victoria Morris; Mary Muldoving; Grace Stewart Mullen; Violet F. Muse; George Addison Newton; Robert Pace; John G. Paine; Louisa Pfau; Robert Porterfield; Wanda Clifton; Sigfrid Prager; Gustave Reese; Hilton Rufty; Hans Schwieger; Lucia W. Smith; Nikolai Sokoloff; Alice Barnett Stevenson; Sidney N. Strotz; Arthur Train; Mrs. Paul J. Weaver; C. B. Wohlford; Karl Wecker.
      - Correspondence, August-December 1941, 35 items. (Box-folder 16:8)
        Correspondents include Ernst Bacon; Bernard Lytton-Bernard; Charles Chapman; Alline Fentress; Kenneth Fiske; Emelyn E. Gardner; Felicia Geffen; Vera Bull Hull; George Pullen Jackson; Roy McAllister; Glenn D. McGeoch; Mrs. Raymond D. McLain; Mrs. A. J. Mooney; Grace Stewart Mullen; Margaret Munn; Bertha E. Nagen; Edouard Nies-Berger; John G. Paine; Jom Rithie; Mrs. Carl E. Sampson; Lucia W. Smith; Reed Smith; Sigmund Spaeth; Russell M. Story; Clara Tovey; J. F. Williamson; Jacques Wolfe.
      - Correspondence, 1940-1941, 65 items. (Box-folder 16:9)
        Correspondents include Isabel Anderson; Adelaide Been; B. W. Bruce; Karl Burger; Charlotte Burleigh; Emmeline Burleigh; Bessie Dudley Burruss; V. S. Chapman; Kay Chase; Chalmers and Wanda Clifton; Beverley Coka; Grace B. Copeland; Elizabeth Adams Elliot; Eugene Field Society; Frances R. Forman; Esther Bley Foy; John D. Green; Ellen Hannah; Alma Hartwell; Elephane Hood; Vera Bull Hull; Louisa Brooke Jones; Ernest LaPrade; Thomas Larkin III; Sarah Leigh; Maud C. Lile; Miss Madeira; Elinor Mason; Mary Mason; Mary Minor; Mary Muldowney; Grace Stewart Mullen; Dorothy Pettus; Seth Preston; Mary Richardson; Tom Ritchie; Reed Smith; Robert P. Wetherald; Carrie Williams; Carrington Williams; Mattie Wohlford.
      - Correspondence, January-March 1942, 43 items. (Box-folder 17:1)
        Correspondents include Dwight Anderson; Mrs. Lewis Carroll Atkisson; Anna L. Baylor; S. M. Bull; Charlie Chapman; James S. Constantine; Elizabeth Crispin; Virginius Dabney; Alice Dukes; Kenneth Fiske; Eloise Florance; Mrs. Walter Golde; Howard Hanson; Vera Bull Hull; Katheryn Johnson; Verbon E. Kemp; Ernest LaPrade; Roy McAllister; Alton C. Morris; Margaret Munn; Robert F. Nelson; John G. Paine; Bessie C. Randolph; Lucy C. P. Scrivenor; Moses Smith; Mabel Martens Snell; Sigmund Spaeth; Theodore E. Steinway; Edward R. Stettinius, Jr.; Mary Stevens; Mabelle S. Wall; Jacques Wolfe.
      - Correspondence, April-July 1942, 19 items. (Box-folder 17:2)
        Correspondents include Beulah Bennett; Harmon Bennet; Harold C. Cobb; M. Estes Cocke; Mary B. Dunlap; James Stone Easley; Elizabeth V. Hamilton; Arthur A. Hauser; Vera Bull Hull; Verbon E. Kemp; Harrison Kerr; Ernest LaPrade; R. C. Lucado; Mary Minor; Henry D. Phillips; Harrison Potter; Carol Preston; Dee Harvey Seugstack; S. Helen Smith.
      - Correspondence, August-December 1942, 28 items. (Box-folder 17:3)
        Correspondents include Dwight Anderson, Dean, University of Louisville; Kitty [Bourgeouis]; Beulah V. Bennett; Shirley Brandt; Betty Buxton; Wanda Clifton; James S. Constantine; Marion Copp; J. Fischer & Brothers; A. W. Greiner, Steinway & Sons; T. Armistead Heindl; Bassett Hough; Vera Bull Hull; J. W. Leake; Jack [John] Longstaff; Daniel Gregory Mason; Franz K. Mohr; Hilton Rufty; Barbara B. Smith; Theodore Steinway; Lamar Stringfield; Deems Taylor, president, ASCAP; Maxwell G. Wallace; Grace F. Wendt; G. F. Wheeler; Robert S. Whitney
        Letters from John Powell to: Armistead Heindl; Steinway.
      - Correspondence, January-February 1943, 23 items. (Box-folder 17:4)
        Correspondents include Dwight Anderson; F. Meredith Dietz; Alice Dukes; Vera Bull Hull; Raymond Kendall; Hilton Rufty; Dabney Wellford, president, The Raven Society; Peggy Wheelwright.
      - Correspondence, March-June 1943, 41 items. (Box-folder 17:5)
        Correspondents include Kitty [Bourgeouis]; Shirley Brandt; Annabel Morris Buchanan; James S. Constantine; Frank M. Flack; Edith Sullivan Golde; Vera Bull Hull; Elizabeth Jervey; Wlademir Lakond; Harold W. Landin; Mrs. Inez Malone; Daniel Gregory Mason; Nathan Oppleman; Sargeant Robert Waldrop; Eva Whitford Lovette; Claire McCarthy; Private David H. Massie, Jr.; Margaret Munn; Vera Palmer; Margot Ragland; Ivie Ray; Hilton Rufty; Barbara Smith; Lamar Stringfield; Annette Hollis Tolman; Private Carrington Williams.
      - Correspondence, July-December 1943, 27 items. (Box-folder 17:6)
        Correspondents include Modest Altschuler; Mrs. Portia Bailey; H. Edward Behre; James S. Constantine; Alice Dukes; Josephine Flexner; Edith Sullivan Golde; Atcheson Hench; Bassett Hough; Claire McCarthy; Catherine Martin; Daniel Gregory Mason; Mrs. Jane Mayer; Earnest Mead; Cadet David H. Massie, Jr.; Seton C. Morris; Nathan Oppleman; Vera Palmer; Hilton Rufty; Barbara Smith; Lamar Stringfield; George Tucker.
      - Correspondence, January-May 1944, 44 items. (Box-folder 17:7)
        Correspondents include Helen De W. Adams; Horton Barker; Paul Brooks, Houghton Mifflin Co.; Richard and Kay Chase; Chalmers and Wanda Clifton; Mary B. Dunlap; Mrs. Richard Florance; Charles E. Griffith; Dan and Betty Grinnan; Besie M. Haupt; Dr. Inez; Jess J. Johnston; Helen Keller; Emma Kerry; Ernest LaPrade; Richard H. Lee; Meary McEldowney; Ernest Mead; Victoria Morris; Margaret Munn; Violet F. Muse; Herbert T. Norris; C. A. Overton; Mary V. Robertson; N. O. Robinson; Mabel Schroetter; [Elma] Sherman; Julian Street; Alfred Swan; H. T. Von Nostrand; Mabel Whitten; Lieutenant G. Carrington Williams; C. B. Wohlford.
      - Correspondence, June-December 1944, 25 items. (Box-folder 17:8)
        Correspondents include Leon Barzin; Mary Bingham; Jeline Maer Bowman; S. M. Bull; C. T. Chapman; Elizabeth Crispin; Alice Dukes; Henry H. Fuchs; J. M. Sailor Dad Hunt; Sister M. Inez; Ernest LaPrade; Casey Lutton; Daniel Gregory Mason; Jake Morris; Hugh Ross; Elizabeth Starritt; C. P. Sterns; Lamar Stringfield; Lillian Williams.
        Letter from John Powell to the Fleisher Music Collection Library.
      - Correspondence, 1942-1944, 49 items. (Box-folder 17:9)
        Correspondents include Mary and Barry Bingham; B. H. Blackwell; [Celine M. Budman]; Charlotte Burleigh; Kay Chase; Jessie Clapperton; Wanda Clifton; Orris Cook; Grace B. Copeland; Grace Louise Cronkhite; Alice Dukes; May Gadd; Carter Sullivan Golde; Agnes [Jardine]; Maude B. Marston; Mary Mason; Sallie [Stephens Perkins]; Myrtice [Persons]; Seth Preston; Helen Reidhenback; Hilton Rufty; Arthur and Lucy Scrivenor, Jr.; Lieutenant A. B. Shepperson; Peggy Smith; Mary Stilinghough; Edna Turpin; Carrie Williams; Paulina Swift Winfield.
      - Correspondence, January-March 1945, 22 items. (Box-folder 17:10)
        Correspondents include Richard Chase; Chalmers Clifton; Wanda Clifton; Corporal Samuel Beverley Cooke II; Constance Darden; Alice Dukes; Mrs. Guy P. Ganett; Helen Havener; Hans Kindler; Janet Ross Johnston; Daniel Gregory Mason; Corporal Nelson A. Miller; Eugene Pillot; Carol Preston; F. H. Price, The Free Library of Philadelphia;Herman [Reichenbactz]; H. N. Shrifte; A. M. Sullivan.
      - Correspondence, April-June 1945, 25 items. (Box-folder 18:1)
        Correspondents include Raimonde Aubrey; Beverley Fleet; Richard A. Carrington, Jr.; Richard Chase; Chalmers Clifton; Elizabeth C. Davenport; Alice Dukes; Carl Fischer; Beverley Fleet; Edith Sullivan Golde; Edith Hill; Kathleen Hoover; Vera Bull Hull; Dick Lee; Earnest Mead; Anna L. Moore; Carol Preston; Seth Preston; Ivie Ray; LaSalle Spier; Hartwell Staples; Lamar Stringfield; Carrie [Williams].
      - Correspondence, July-December 1945, 20 items. (Box-folder 18:2)
        Correspondents include Kitty Blanton Bruce; Walter Buxbaum; Orris Cook; Elizabeth Crispin; Francis Warrington Dawson; Alice Dukes; Charles W. Freeman; Mrs. Guy P. Gannett; Earnest Mead; F. H. Price; Laura B. Tate; June Burkett Van Kirk; Frank Wendt.
      - Correspondence, January-July 1946, 50 items. (Box-folder 18:3)
        Correspondents include Helen De W. Adams; John W. Beattie, Dean, Northwestern University; Winifred Bogert; Margaret Stanley Brown; Dudley Burruss; Wanda and Chalmers Clifton; Grace Potter Carroll; Elizabeth Crispin; Joseph A. Fischer; William Garrard; Ida Harrell Hoffman; Bassett Hough; Vera Bull Hull; Janet R. Johnston; Christl Kerry; Pritzi [Kerry]; Ernest LaPrade; Dick Lee; Daniel I. McNamara; Doris Neale; Seth Preston; Bill Ralston; Florence Robertson; Cuthbert Powell Stearns; Lamar Stringfield; Lucy Ann Taylor; Rosalie Thornton; George Tucker; Frank Wendt; J. F. Williamson.
      - Correspondence, August-December 1946, 43 items. (Box-folder 18:4)
        Correspondents include Richard Chase; Chase Freeland Chapman Conference; Wanda Clifton; Composers Authors Guild; Mr. and Mrs. James Walter Cranor; Elizabeth Crispin; Eugene H. Fischer; Mrs. Guy P. Gannett; Inez Hadley; Bessie Haupt; Helen Havener; Vera Bull Hull; Polly Hunter; Ben B. Johnson, Jr.; Sarah Leigh; Hallie B. McMillian; Hallie B. McMillian to Vera Bull Hull; Daniel Gregory Mason to editor, The Musical Digest; Franz Karl Mohr; Vera Palmer; Hilton Rufty; Edna Shaeffer; Edward R. Stettinius, Jr.; George Tucker.
        Letters from John Powell to: Mrs. Fluorney; Mrs. Guy P. Gannett.
      - Correspondence, January-February 1947, 26 items. (Box-folder 18:5)
        Correspondents include Carrie Virginia Anderson, Richmond Public Library; Virginia Clinton; T. E. Cronk, Westminster Choir College, New Jersey; Francis Warrington Dawson; Eleanor Fitzgerald; Helen L. Gunderson, Louisiana State University; Helen Havener; Francis S. Hutchins, Berea College, Kentucky; Thomas B. McAdams; Hallie B. McMillian; Alpha C. Mayfield; Mrs. William Robert Owen; F.H. Price, Free Library of Philadelphia; Lamar Stringfield.
        Letter from John Powell to: Miss Havener.
      - Correspondence, March-April 1947, 51 items. (Box-folder 18:6)
        Correspondents include Martha R. Adams; Charles Barham, Jr.; Mary and Barry Bingham; Mrs. James M. Boles; Carol Bridgeman; Carrie Lee Campbell; Jean Carrington, student; Kate F. Chase; Chalmers Clifton; Elizabeth Crispin; Kenneth E. Crouch; Elizabeth C. Davenport; Francis Warrington Dawson; Alice Dukes; S. H. and Grace Fereber; Edith Sullivan Golde, Leschetizky Association; Mr. and Mrs. Gravatts; R. L. Harrison; Helen Havener; Leliane Haynes; Edith Hill; Rose Horner; Vera Bull Hull; Ernest Hutcheson; Hans Kindler; Ernest LaPrade; Bill and Mabel Maloney; Alpha C. Mayfield, Southwestern Louisiana Institute; Daniel and Mary Mason; Martha Maynard; T. Tertius Noble; Vera Palmer; James Christian Pfohl; Jessie and Cuthbert [Powell]; Carol Preston; Seth Preston; Luther A. Richman; Hilton Rufty [and Adeline]; Arcule G. [Steaslie]; Nellie [Shatlford] Smith; Robert L. Stearns, University of Colorado; Edward R. Stettinius, Jr.; Lamar Stringfield; Annette Talman; Rosalie Thornton; Emma Gray Trigg; Constance J. Watson.
        Letters from John Powell to: Mary and Barry Bingham; Dr. Karl Krueger; Edward R. Stettinius, Jr.
      - Correspondence, May-August 1947, 36 items. (Box-folder 18:7)